imcpl.org 2017-12-03

# E-Privacy Statement | The Indianapolis Public LIbrary

The Indianapolis Public Library (IndyPL) provides this web site as a public service. IndyPL respects the privacy of every individual who visits our web sites. We do not collect personal information about you when you visit our web sites unless you choose to provide such information.

## What is Personal Information?

Personal information is any personally identifiable information about you (that is, your name, address, telephone number, or email address), unless you provide it to us voluntarily.

## Children

IndyPL has no intention of collecting any personally identifiable information (that is, name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address) from individuals under 13 years of age. Where appropriate, IndyPL will specifically instruct children not to submit such information on our web site. If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information, a parent or guardian of that child should contact us at the e-mail address or phone number listed at the bottom of this Policy if they would like this information deleted from our records. We will use reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from our existing files.

## Collection of Personal Information

### Statistical Information

Statistical information is collected and used by IndyPL for the purpose of managing and improving service operations and to report statistics regarding the use of IndyPL web sites. Web site access information is automatically logged by servers and software programs. The information gathered does not identify individual visitors by name. Information collected includes but is not limited to: IP addresses, date and time of access, operating systems, browser types and versions, access duration, and the domain name of the web site from which you linked to our web site. Persistent cookies (discussed in more detail below) may be used to further gather statistical information about web site usage.

### Personally Identifiable Information

When you visit an IndyPL web site, we do not collect any personally identifiable information without your consent. Individuals may choose to submit personally identifiable information such as name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address in order to receive services such as purchase suggestions, event registration, and e-mail notifications.

Occasionally, we offer the opportunity to contribute to the content of our web site. Your submission of any such content for publication would be entirely voluntary on your part. However, unless you specifically request that your personally identifiable information is withheld from such publication, any information you submit will not be subject to the protections of this e-privacy statement.

Credit card details collected via electronic forms on IndyPL web sites are encrypted using secure server technology. Only the last 4 digits of the credit card number entered is stored. This information is only made accessible to staff members authorized to complete the transaction.

## Use of Personal Information

IndyPL collects personal information for the purpose of operating the web site and delivering requested services. IndyPL does not sell, rent, or otherwise distribute or disclose this information to outside companies or organizations unless legally required to do so or with the consumer's consent.

### Non-Persistent Cookies

When you view our web site we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a ?cookie? or similar file and will help us in many ways. With most Internet browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. Non-persistent cookies may be used on IndyPL web sites to manage a user?s session. These cookies are only necessary to maintain session information. Non-persistent cookies are temporary and are invalidated after you have closed your web browser.

If you decide to disable cookies while using an IndyPL web site, you will still be able to use the IndyPL web site, but will not be able to use cookie dependent features.

### Persistent Cookies

IndyPL may use persistent cookies in order to gather statistics regarding its web site usage in order to improve our users? online experiences. No personal identification information is captured by IndyPL through the use of persistent cookies.

### Other Web Sites

IndyPL's web site contains links to other web sites. IndyPL is not responsible for the content or privacy policies of other sites. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that site.

## Whom to Contact

Further questions? Contact the IndyPL Webmaster.

_Revised December 20, 2016_
